GRAHAM A. SCHMIDT

38 Day St. Apt 30, Somerville, MA, 02144 Phone: (516) 672-4855 schmidtg@gmail.com http://www.schmidtg.com

"I'm smart, reliable and get things done."

Full Stack Web Developer: Over 10+ years experience in web development, graphic design and team leadership. I often earn a "go-to" role for teams that I join. I'm constantly self-learning and challenging myself everyday to be the most effective software engineer. I take pride in delivering results, and I communicate proactively to ensure that expectations are met regularly.

RELEVANT SKILLS AND ACHIEVEMENTS

- Specialties: PHP, MySQL, Javascript/Ajax, jQuery, HTML/CSS, Git, MVC, Internet technologies
- Passion for developing seemless User experiences that leverage innovative web technologies
- Formal training in both graphic design and computer science
- Dedicated and hard-working individual who delivers polished results every time
- Highly self-motivated and constantly looking to make things better

RELEVANT WORK EXPERIENCE

Back-end Engineer

September 2011 – Present

Hungry Fish Media, LLC / NutraClick

- Write, maintain and optimize PHP scripts to handle automation and management of large datasets
- Lead developer for Magento Enterprise e-commerce site (www.healthexperts.com)
- Built various support tools for handling management of 15,000+ SKU catalog
- Shared lead development (Zend) for building self-serve 'Membership' site of 30,000+ users
- Earned greater responsibility for independently managing the completion of major projects

Senior Front-End Engineer

September 2010 – 2011

Hungry Fish Media, LLC

- Built numerous business tools and reports using the Flourish PHP framework, AJAX, and custom javascript namespaced objects
- Rigorously tested and improved landing pages on a daily basis using an in-house analytics A/B testing platform along with Google Analytics
- Refactored existing codebase to be more object-oriented for greater code reuse
- Crafted hand-coded pages (VIM, Chrome Dev, Firebug) in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript for superior readability, rapid development and ease of maintenance
- Progressed to senior front-end developer after only 6 months in the front-end role, and coordinated the hiring of new team members and taking on senior duties

Graphic Designer

September 2009 – September 2010

Hungry Fish Media, LLC

- Regularly created numerous Landing Pages and web advertisements for display on large websites such as MSN.com, Yahoo.com, and AOL which generated some of the highest clickthru rates and lead acquisitions in the company's history
- Created a successful landing page in one work day that went on to become the fastest growing lead acquisition website by the company
- Created various print, promotional and packaging materials that helped establish one of the top selling nutritional sports supplement brands in GNC stores nationwide

[September 2008 – September 2009 travelled throughout India, Nepal, NZ, Africa]

Web Developer and Graphic Designer

January 2007 - August 2008

Bedlam Paintball / Nationwide Paintball (Edinburgh, Scotland)

- Co-ordinated a successful delivery of a £30k+ project to deliver an Oracle-based online booking system in which massive company data and services relied upon
- Further developed an existing PHP-based booking system which enabled Sales agents to save 30 minutes of administrative work and greatly improve their efficiency
- Created attractive competition-based landing pages for Blockbuster movie promotions that collected thousands of sales leads and heavily contributed towards a turnover of £15-20k for those specific campaigns

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Concepts: UX/UI architecture, wireframing, Front-end engineering, MVC, AJAX, OOP, JSON, Singlepage Apps, Version control (Git), REST, Database design, Agile, Scrum, SEO, CMS, Big Data,

Visualization, Web architecture, Functional programming

Software/IDEs: MacVim, Git, Sublime, Intellij IDEA, Emacs, Photoshop, Flash Languages: PHP, Javascript, C, Java, SQL, HTML5, CSS3, XML, RegEx, Actionscript

Databases/Servers: MySQL, MSSQL, Apache, Mac OS X

Frameworks/Libraries: Zend, Flourish (PHP), Codelgniter, Laravel, ¡Query, ¡Query mobile, Prototype,

YUI, Backbone.js, Underscore.js, Handlebars.js, Twitter Bootstrap, SASS Platforms: Magento, Wordpress, Expression Engine, Drupal, Etomite/ModX

APIs: Google Maps, Magento, Paypal, Twitter, Litle

Testing Tools: Chrome Dev Tools, Firebug, New Relic, Selenium, Xdebug, JSLint, Google Analytics

RECENT PERSONAL PROJECT URLS

LexPress mobile app (PHP, JS, ¡Query mobile) http://www.schmidtg.com/lexpress/app/ Eventry.net registration system (Codeigniter) CMAP LLC (Wordpress)

http://www.eventry.net/ http://www.cmapllc.com/

EDUCATION

Graduate-Level Coursework

2011 - Present

Harvard University Extension School (Cambridge, MA)

Java for Distributed Computing, Data structures, Intensive Intro to CS (pre-reg)

Bsc Computer Science (great distinction, *85% average)

Awarded 2005

- *My university does not use grade-point average but instead gives an overall percentage University of Regina (Canada)
 - Software Engineering, Human Computer Interaction, Visualization, Databases

Multimedia Certificate

Awarded 2003

Applied Multimedia Centre (Canada)

• Graphic design, page layout, typography, sound editing, 3D animation

TRANSFERABLE SKILLS

- Fast learner and incredibly resourceful
- Excellent communication skills
- Able to manage time and resources efficiently
- Independent, reliable and very hard-working

ACTIVITIES & INTERESTS

Adventure travel, cooking, hiking, homebrewing, bagpiping

REFERENCES

Available upon request